<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Internal functions</name>
		<description>Internal funtions</description>
		<author url="">Internal</author>
		<update version="1.0.1">
			<file name="internal-2024.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/caiapha/Aurora_PHB24/refs/heads/main/Players-Hanbook/internal-2024.xml" />
		</update>
		<author url="https://marketplace.dndbeyond.com/core-rules/3709000">Wizards of the Coast</author>
	</info>
    <element name="Darkvision" type="Vision" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_PHB24_VISION_DARKVISION">
		<requirements>!ID_PHB24_VISION_SUPERIORDARKVISION</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>Many creatures in the worlds of D&amp;D, especially those that dwell underground, have darkvision. Within a specified range, a creature with darkvision can see in darkness as if the darkness were dim light, so areas of darkness are only lightly obscured as far as that creature is concerned. However, the creature can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can see in dim light within {{darkvision:range}} feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="darkvision:range" value="60" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

    <element name="Superior Darkvision" type="Vision" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_PHB24_VISION_SUPERIORDARKVISION">
		<description>
			<p>Many creatures in the worlds of D&amp;D, especially those that dwell underground, have darkvision. Within a specified range, a creature with darkvision can see in darkness as if the darkness were dim light, so areas of darkness are only lightly obscured as far as that creature is concerned. However, the creature can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can see in dim light within {{darkvision:range}} feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="darkvision:range" value="120" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

    <element name="Blindsight" type="Vision" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_PHB24_VISION_BLINDSIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>A creature with blindsight can perceive its surroundings without relying on sight, within a specific radius. Creatures without eyes, such as oozes, and creatures with echolocation or heightened senses, such as bats and true dragons, have this sense.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You perceive your surroundings within {{blindsight:range}} feet without relying on sight.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="blindsight:range" value="0" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

    <element name="Truesight" type="Vision" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_PHB24_VISION_TRUESIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>A creature with truesight can, out to a specific range, see in normal and magical darkness, see invisible creatures and objects, automatically detect visual illusions and succeed on saving throws against them, and perceives the original form of a shapechanger or a creature that is transformed by magic. Furthermore, the creature can see into the Ethereal Plane.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can see in normal and magical darkness, see invisible creatures and objects, automatically detect visual illusions and succeed on saving throws against them, and perceives the original form of a shapechanger or a creature that is transformed by magic within {{truesight:range}} feet. Furthermore, the creature can see into the Ethereal Plane.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="truesight:range" value="0" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

    <element name="Tremorsense" type="Vision" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_PHB24_VISION_TREMORSENSE">
		<description>
			<p>A monster with tremorsense can detect and pinpoint the origin of vibrations within a specific radius, provided that the monster and the source of the vibrations are in contact with the same ground or substance.</p>
			<p class="indent">Tremorsense can't be used to detect flying or incorporeal creatures. Many burrowing creatures, such as ankhegs, have this special sense.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can detect and pinpoint the origin of vibrations within {{tremorsense:range}} feet, provided that the monster and the source of the vibrations are in contact with the same ground or substance. Tremorsense can't be used to detect flying or incorporeal creatures.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="tremorsense:range" value="0" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- ALIGNMENTS -->	
	<element name="Lawful Good" type="Alignment" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ALIGNMENT_LG"> 
		<description>
			<p>Un personaggio legale buono rispetta leggi e codici morali e usa l’ordine per proteggere gli innocenti e promuovere il bene.</p>
		</description> 
		<setters>	 
			<set name="abbreviation">LG</set> 
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Neutral Good" type="Alignment" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ALIGNMENT_NG">
		<description>
			<p>Un personaggio neutrale buono fa il bene secondo coscienza, senza essere rigidamente vincolato né alla legge né al caos.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">NG</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Chaotic Good" type="Alignment" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ALIGNMENT_CG">
		<description>
			<p>Un personaggio caotico buono segue il cuore e la libertà, pronto a infrangere regole ingiuste pur di aiutare gli altri.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">CG</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Lawful Neutral" type="Alignment" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ALIGNMENT_LN"> 
		<description>
			<p>Un personaggio legale neutrale mette al primo posto ordine, tradizione e dovere, sopra considerazioni di bene o male personali.</p>
		</description> 
		<setters>	 
			<set name="abbreviation">LN</set> 
		</setters>   
	</element>

	<element name="Neutral" type="Alignment" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ALIGNMENT_N"> 
		<description>
			<p>Un personaggio neutrale cerca equilibrio o disinteresse, non si schiera in modo deciso tra bene e male, legge e caos.</p>
		</description> 
		<setters>	 
			<set name="abbreviation">N</set> 
		</setters>   
	</element>

	<element name="Chaotic Neutral" type="Alignment" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ALIGNMENT_CN"> 
		<description>
			<p>Un personaggio caotico neutrale è imprevedibile, indipendente e guidato dal desiderio di libertà personale sopra ogni regola o autorità.</p>
		</description> 
		<setters>	 
			<set name="abbreviation">CN</set> 
		</setters>   
	</element>

	<element name="Lawful Evil" type="Alignment" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ALIGNMENT_LE"> 
		<description>
			<p>Un personaggio legale malvagio usa gerarchie, leggi e patti per ottenere potere e controllo, sfruttando gli altri senza rimorso.</p>
		</description> 
		<setters>	 
			<set name="abbreviation">LE</set> 
		</setters>   
		</element>

	<element name="Neutral Evil" type="Alignment" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ALIGNMENT_NE"> 
		<description>
			<p>Un personaggio neutrale malvagio pensa solo a sé stesso, pronto a tradire, mentire o danneggiare chiunque serva ai suoi fini.</p>
		</description> 
		<setters>	 
			<set name="abbreviation">NE</set> 
		</setters>   
	</element>
	
	<element name="Chaotic Evil" type="Alignment" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_ALIGNMENT_CE">
		<description>
			<p>Un personaggio caotico malvagio è distruttivo, imprevedibile e spinto dall’istinto di rovinare, dominare o annientare.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">CE</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>



