<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <update version="1.0.0">
      <file name="sorcerer-wild_magic-2024.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/caiapha/Aurora_PHB24/refs/heads/main/Players-Hanbook/sorcerer-wild_magic-2024.xml" />
    </update>
    <author url="https://marketplace.dndbeyond.com/core-rules/3709000">Wizards of the Coast</author>
  </info>

  <!-- ===================== WILD MAGIC SORCERY (PHB 2024) ===================== -->
  <element name="Wild Magic Sorcery" type="Archetype" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_WILD_MAGIC">
    <supports>SorcererSubclass</supports>
    <description>
      <h1>Wild Magic Sorcery</h1>
      <p>Unleash surges of chaotic arcane power.</p>

      <h3>Subclass Features</h3>
      <p>When you choose this subclass at 3rd level, you gain the following features.</p>

      <div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_WILD_MAGIC_SURGE" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_TIDES_OF_CHAOS" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_BEND_LUCK" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_CONTROLLED_CHAOS" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_TAMED_SURGE" />
    </description>

    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_WILD_MAGIC_SURGE" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_TIDES_OF_CHAOS"    level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_BEND_LUCK"        level="6" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_CONTROLLED_CHAOS"  level="14" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_TAMED_SURGE"       level="18" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <!-- ===== Level 3: Wild Magic Surge ===== -->
  <element name="Wild Magic Surge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_WILD_MAGIC_SURGE">
    <description>
      <p>Your spellcasting can unleash surges of untamed magic. No more than once per turn, immediately after you cast a Sorcerer spell using a spell slot, roll a d20. On a 20, roll on the Wild Magic Surge table to create a magical effect (see the Player's Handbook for that table). If the effect is a spell, it is too wild to be affected by your Metamagic. If it normally requires Concentration, it does not require Concentration for this surge and lasts its full duration.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>After you cast a Sorcerer spell with a slot, roll d20; on 20, roll on the Wild Magic Surge table. Surge-spells ignore Metamagic and do not require Concentration.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <!-- ===== Level 3: Tides of Chaos ===== -->
  <element name="Tides of Chaos" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_TIDES_OF_CHAOS">
    <description>
      <p>You can manipulate the forces of chance and chaos to gain Advantage on one d20 Test. Once you do so, you must finish a Long Rest before you can use this feature again. Immediately after you cast a Sorcerer spell with a spell slot before you regain the use of this feature, you automatically roll on the Wild Magic Surge table and then regain the use of this feature.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
      <description>You gain Advantage on one d20 Test. If you cast a Sorcerer spell with a slot before you regain this feature, you automatically roll on the Wild Magic Surge table and then this feature recharges.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <!-- ===== Level 6: Bend Luck ===== -->
  <element name="Bend Luck" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_BEND_LUCK">
    <description>
      <p>You have the ability to twist fate using your wild magic. Immediately after another creature you can see rolls the d20 for a D20 Test, you can take a Reaction and spend 1 Sorcery Point to roll 1d4 and apply the number rolled as a bonus or penalty (your choice) to the d20 roll.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet action="Reaction">
      <description>After a creature you can see rolls a d20 Test, spend 1 Sorcery Point to apply ±1d4 (your choice) to the roll.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <!-- ===== Level 14: Controlled Chaos ===== -->
  <element name="Controlled Chaos" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_CONTROLLED_CHAOS">
    <description>
      <p>You gain a modicum of control over the surges of your wild magic. Whenever you roll on the Wild Magic Surge table, you can roll twice and use either number.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you roll on the Wild Magic Surge table, roll twice and choose either result.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <!-- ===== Level 18: Tamed Surge ===== -->
  <element name="Tamed Surge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player's Handbook (2024)" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SORCERER_WILD_MAGIC_FEATURE_TAMED_SURGE">
    <description>
      <p>Immediately after you cast a Sorcerer spell with a spell slot, you can create an effect of your choice from the Wild Magic Surge table instead of rolling on that table. You can choose any effect in the table except for the final row, and if the chosen effect involves a roll, you must make it.</p>
      <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.</p>  
    </description>
    <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
      <description>After you cast a Sorcerer spell with a slot, you can choose a Wild Magic Surge effect, except for the last entry. </description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

</elements>



